<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The Coding Disappointment]]></title><description><![CDATA[A personal little blog to post my various coding adventures and mishaps, as well as any random tidbits from my life.]]></description><link>https://sabarnac.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 21:27:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[A PoC Beginning]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do note that starting from just a PoC is not always possible for every scenario and every project, but a starting point to see if something…]]></description><link>https://sabarnac.github.io/2019/01/03/a-poc-beginning/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sabarnac.github.io/2019/01/03/a-poc-beginning/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 19:39:48 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do note that starting from just a PoC is not always possible for every scenario and every project, but a starting point to see if something can work or not is a big benefit nonetheless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://memegenerator.net/img/instances/67101634/brace-yourselves-a-proof-of-concept-is-coming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PoC Meme&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A “Proof of Concept” (PoC) is a term that most programmers are familiar with. If not, there’s multiple articles online that describe a concept (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_concept&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;), and many that describe the benefits, this being one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A PoC, while not always possible or required to create before starting a project, can provide a ton of benefits to a developer in figuring out their project, from a high-level design and requirements down to even low-level component design. The obvious benefit is that as a PoC is built, the requirements of the application become well understood and a clear higher-level design can be crafted based on experience from building the PoC. This experience can also benefit low-level component design, since understanding how the software has to function can help figure out how components have to be made to ensure a high enough quality for the project is maintained, which is great for reducing your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;WTFs/min&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.osnews.com/story/19266/WTFs_m&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://blog.codinghorror.com/content/images/uploads/2009/02/6a0120a85dcdae970b012877707a45970c-pi.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Donal Knuth&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoCs can also help reduce development time over the long run, since this experience and understanding can help speeden development as fewer changes and mistakes are made throughout the development lifecycle. If a PoC is built well enough from the ground up, iterations of that PoC can be done to further speeden development and prevent the need to rebuild from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dependencies required to build the project can also be locked with the help of a PoC, since it is only during the development of the product that all the required dependencies of it can be fully realised. Otherwise, new dependencies may pop up mid-development, and integration of them can be costly since they may require a refactor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoCs can also help people have a better understanding of the idea and product the PoC represents, which allows for early feedback. This feedback is crucial for development, since it’s early enough in the development stage that implementing that feedback can be done relatively easily and incorporated within the design itself. The early feedback also helps bring a much needed perspective from potential users, who can correct an improper understanding of a product or idea, which can allow for early course correction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the most important benefit of a PoC is a part of the name itself - a proof that the idea works and is viable. Without a clear understanding of whether a product can work, the future of it is uncertain, and to determine that a PoC is highly beneficial. A PoC doesn’t have to be the final product, it just has to show that the final product is possible. A PoC isn’t a prototype either, since a prototype just showcases certain features, while a PoC should show the overall concept and idea of the product as a whole. The fact that the PoC is built is enough to show the potential of the product, and without that knowledge being able to sell an idea becomes significantly harder.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Create To Maintain]]></title><description><![CDATA[XKCD - Donal Knuth Always code with maintenance in mind, even if it’s for a small project that you’ll only be touching once and then…]]></description><link>https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/23/create-to-maintain/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/23/create-to-maintain/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 15:07:33 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xkcd.com/163/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/donald_knuth.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Donal Knuth&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always code with maintenance in mind, even if it’s for a small project that you’ll only be touching once and then ignoring forever. You may never know when you’ll suddenly need to use it again, and then regret not having made it a lot more simple to understand and change. The biggest benefit is to make it simple and elegant, and writing code in such a way that reading the code without any comments would still be enough to understand what it’s doing. Avoid clever tricks that don’t really provide a benefit, or else provide detailed information along with the clever bits of code so that people can understand what’s going in with all that complicated mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/844/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/good_code.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Good Code&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this is something not everyone always keeps in mind (including me). Sometimes writing the code as fast as possible without much care about readability is more important than making it maintainable, since you may just plan to just “code, compile, use and forget” whatever you’re doing, or maybe even because time constraints for a project force you to decide to refactor the code at a later point. For some of these cases, it is mostly fine, and you may actually be better off writing it again rather than changing what’s already there if you intend to use it more seriously. In other cases, it can lead to a lot of problems later on, and result in regrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1319/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/automation.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Automation&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing code in preparation for maintaining it later on results in not only lesser hastle for you in the future, but also allows you to pass it on to others who can work on it too without much difficulty. Someone else could take it over and continue working on it without constant confusion on how stuff works. If you ever need to modify it and use it later on, you’ll be thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem, however, is not actually writing code that’s maintainable, it’s getting into the mindset to always write maintainable code. We generally forgo maintainability for small projects because we feel there’s no need to go through that effort. However, if we always push ourselves to do so, not only do we ensure that we’ll have no problems later on if we have to go back to it. You can also do it as practice for real projects, figuring out the best ways to get great code quality. It all starts with you deciding to make it so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if only I followed what I preach.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Brainfuck Interpreter]]></title><description><![CDATA[Brainfuck, it's easy as 1-2-3 I’m sure you’ve heard of this simple little esoteric programming language, or at least seen that garble of…]]></description><link>https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/08/a-brainfuck-interpreter/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/08/a-brainfuck-interpreter/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 06:32:10 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/ctCM6rb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ctCM6rb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Brainfuck, it&amp;#x27;s easy as 1-2-3&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you’ve heard of this simple little &lt;em&gt;esoteric&lt;/em&gt; programming language, or at least seen that garble of text somewhere whenever there’s a discussion on languages that wanna make you tear your hair out. While it’s not Malbolge levels of torture, it’s simple construct can actually be really confusing to deal with if you don’t track what’s happening carefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a quick look at the language. There are no identifiers, syntax or anything like any programming language you would use for real applications. Only eight basic commands are used in Brainfuck - ”.”, ”,”, ”+”, ”-”, ”&gt;”, ”&amp;#x3C;”, ”[” and ”]”. All data related operations occur on an (theoretically) infinite sequence of cells, making it operate similar to a Turing machine. Using the eight commands, you can perform various tasks, and the language is Turing complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the commands are very simple, if the task becomes even slightly complex, the code can look very messy or very confusing, depending if you want to keep the code simple or efficient. So, although theoretically the language can perform a wide range of tasks, you obviously wouldn’t want to use it anyways because of the problems it can cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing that all the language consists of only single character commands, coding a compiler and interpreter should be pretty simple. The only real problem is having infinite cells for the program to write into. This could be solved through dynamic allocation of cells as and when required, and this is limited by the heap memory available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided, since this was a very simple language, to write a interpreter and compiler for it. First I started off with the interpreter, seeing that it would be simpler. I created some basic basic data structures for use by the interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A data structure for the nodes of the cell that form a double linked list, for two-way traveral.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    uint8_t value&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;                            &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The value of the node in the list.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;previous_node&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The pointer to the previous node in the list, if any.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;next_node&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The pointer to the next node in the list, if any.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A data structure for the loop control that form a stack. The nodes just store the position in the program file where the loop starts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;loop_stack_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt; start_pointer_position&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;           &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The input pointer position for the start of the loop.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;loop_stack_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;outer_loop_node&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The pointer to the outer loop of the loop, if any.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A data structure to store the instruction pointers’ current positiona and value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;input_pointer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;long&lt;/span&gt; position&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Current position of the input pointer.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;      value&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Value of the character in the current input position.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A data structure for storing the source file pointer, the instruction pointer details as well as the interpreter status and message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;input_file&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    FILE                 &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;source&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The program file being interpreted.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;input_pointer&lt;/span&gt; pointer&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The current input position details.&lt;/span&gt;
    uint8_t              status&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The status of the program being interpreted.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;char&lt;/span&gt;                 message&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;65536&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//A message about the current status of the program being interpreted.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A data structure that stores the current cells’ address and the top loops’ address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list_node&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;list_position&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The pointer to the current position in the program list.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;loop_stack_node&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;loop_top&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The pointer to the current position in the loop.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, a data structure that contains the previous two data structures, as well as the program input and output files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_details&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;input_file&lt;/span&gt;   file&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The program file.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;program_list&lt;/span&gt; list&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The program list&lt;/span&gt;
    FILE                &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;progin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The program input file.&lt;/span&gt;
    FILE                &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;progout&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//The program output file.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program quickly checks whether certain parameters have been provided. These then get passed to an initializer function that sets up the values of the data structures. Control is then handed over to the interpreter execution function, which uses the rules of the language dispersed through various functions to execute the brainfuck code. Upon completion, a cleanup function to clear away the data structures is called and finally the interpreter ends its execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; argc &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; argc &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Check if parameters have been provided for interpretation and execution of a program.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;interpreter_init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;argv&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; output&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; input&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Initialize the interpreter.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;interpreter_exec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;                       &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Execute the interpreter.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;interpreter_clean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;                      &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Clean up after the interpreter.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; program&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;file&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;status&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;               &lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;//Return the final program status.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only one kind of error that can occur in a Brainfuck program, and that’s unmatched loop braces. The program handles this by halting execution and terminating immediately, with an error message stating the error and the byte location where the error occured. The interpreter can also run out of heap memory for execution. There is no error handling for such a situation, which I need to take care of. This error can be temporarily fixed by compiling the interpreter code to start out with more heap memory so as to overflow on it. It’s not the perfect solution, but it’ll do and is better than just throwing an error for such type of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another kind of error can occur - when the source file or program input file cannot be opened. This also leads to halting of the program and termination. The only change required here is to allow non-existence of a program file input IF the Brainfuck program requires no input. Parsing through the entire file searching for even a single input command should work for this case, although for very lengthy programs it can take time. Another option is to not care and start execution until an input is requested, and only throw an error when such a scenario is reached. I’ll most likely opt for the latter approach, since it keeps things simpler and faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interpreter source code, along with a Windows and Linux executable, is available at Github. The Windows executuble was compiled using Orwell Dev-C++, and the Linux executable was compiled using GCC 5.4.0 on the Ubuntu Linux Layer added onto Windows with no changes in C code between the two (since I did try to ensure to use simple, cross-platform code).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compiler side of things may be a bit trickier to implement. The lexical, syntax and semantic analysis can be skipped, since all commands are independent and single character only, allowing for super simple parsing. The only problem to deal with is handling the sequence of cells, although I do have an idea for that. I also plan to compile to LLVM, to allow for platform-agnostic compilation. The LLVM code then be compiled manually to machine dependent code which I will leave to the end user of the compiler. However, I don’t plan on starting working on the compiler anytime soon, and optimizations to the interpreter won’t be a priority for me as well, since I plan to work on a mini-learning project in Unity just to get a hang of things with the engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link to the Github repo with the complete code and executables is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sabarnac/brainf-interpreter-compiler&quot;&gt;https://github.com/sabarnac/brainf-interpreter-compiler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you guys have a good day! :D&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to My Blog!]]></title><description><![CDATA[XKCD - Code Quality Welcome! I decided to start this personal little blog to post my various coding adventures and mishaps,
as well as any…]]></description><link>https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/01/welcome-to-my-blog/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://sabarnac.github.io/2017/05/01/welcome-to-my-blog/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1513/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/code_quality.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Code Quality&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome! I decided to start this personal little blog to post my various coding adventures and mishaps,
as well as any random tidbits from my life. Hopefully, the posts here won’t make you feel like the name
of this blog is right, although I do have a feeling a few of the posts I have or will post may do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do share your thoughts and opinions on anything I post and feel free to contact me as long as it doesn’t disappoint. I may occasionally steal and share certain memes and posts that catch my eye from places like Reddit (Just kidding, I’ll make sure to link the source). Don’t expect my blog posts to always make sense, in both structure as well as story (just like this one :P). Feel free to complain about that too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Jekyll bootstrap blog took a little longer than I expected to set up. The default packaged themes provided were terribly outdated. Luckily, they are up-to-date on GitHub, so a simple download and switch to the current theme (which I personally like the most among the choices for this bootstrap), and a bit of fiddling around to get my blog pages just how I want them, and voila! An initial blog I’m pretty OK with. Good thing I decided to do this right during my exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do plan to figure out the theme API for this bootstrap and create my own theme for the blog at one point. Hopefully, I’ll actually get around to doing it soon. I might also change the structure a little bit more and add and remove things here and there to keep things just the way I want them to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I won’t regret this later on in life. For now I guess I’ll just have to enjoy the ride and hope for the best. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/1421/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/future_self.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD - Future Self&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>